Finding Aid for Dentistry Library (University of Michigan) records, 1925-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Library Collection 1925-1997
  - Student Term Papers -- Bound 1941-1972
    - Shaffer, Ronald P., Risks Involved in Dental Roentgenography December 1963 (Box 9)
    - Smalley, James W., Natal and Neonatal Teeth March 1967 (Box 9)
    - Smutko, G. E., Radiography in Dental Prosthetics January 15, 1959 (Box 9)
    - Stone, John W., Posterior Bite-wing Survey of the Primary Teeth as a Technic for the Public Health Dentist undated (Box 9)
    - Stromberg, W. Ross, Importance of Roentgenology for the Edentulous Patient January 1952 (Box 9)
    - Summers, Charles W., Is it Possible to Overdevelop Dental Roentgenograms? January 1960 (Box 9)
    - Taylor, Louis E., Tissue Changes Shown through Application of Mechanical Forces January 14, 1948 (Box 9)
    - Taylor, Paul P., Seconal: A Sedative for Children Receiving Root Surgery January 25, 1950 (Box 9)
    - Taylor, Paul P., Sedation in the Management of the Child Dental Patient January 16, 1950 (Box 9)
    - Torgerson, T. S., Osteomyelitis of the Jaws undated (Box 9)
    - Trejos, Rodolfo, Should Every Cleft Palate be Operated Surgically? January 1958 (Box 9)
    - Valencia, Jaime, The Permanent Central Incisor in Cleft Palate June 1955 (Box 9)
    - Van Noord, A. G., Congenital and Developmental Deformities of the Head Face and Jaws January 18, 1956 (Box 9)
    - Vandersluis, R. W., The Effect of Certain Unanswered Questions in the Behavioral Sciences upon Dental Public Health Programs: Motivation to Take a Health-related Action December 13, 1968 (Box 9)
    - Viloria, Jorge, A Study of the Relationship of Raphe Palatinus to the Craniofacial Skeleton June 1, 1955 (Box 9)
    - Way, David C., Cephalometric Roentgenography in Orthodontics January 1952 (Box 9)
    - Wehner, Paul J., Radiation Overexposure and its Effects on Tissues, Organs, and Glands of the Head and Neck undated (Box 9)
    - Weiss, Allen W., Osteomyelitis: The Disease and its Radiographic Manifestations January 1956 (Box 9)
    - Westover, Ransom M., Determination of Maturation Rates of Children who need Orthodontic Treatment undated (Box 9)
    - Wong, Ted, A Rationale for Base Stability December 11, 1974 (Box 9)
    - Yong, Siu Len, Cherubism March 1967 (Box 9)
    - Youngblood, P. J., Recent Studies on the Effects of Radiation on the Jaws and Teeth January 18, 1958 (Box 9)
- Library Services 1947-2006
  The Library Services series, 1947-2006 (1.75 linear feet), is comprised of documents relating to the services provided by the Dentistry Library. These services include bibliographic instruction, acquisitions, serials management, circulation statistics, and reference. This series contains records relating to library collections, policies, procedures, statistics, and instruction.
  - Acquisitions 1994-1998 (Box 10)
  - Annual Volume Count Statistics 1985-1995 (Box 10)
  - Bibliographic Instruction 1988-1997
    - Handouts and Guides undated (Box 10)
    - Introduction to Minority Resources 1992 (Box 10)
    - Introduction to U.S. Government Documents in the Health Sciences 1992 (Box 10)
    - User Education Activity Report 1995-1996 (Box 10)
    - User Education Activity Record 1996-1997 (Box 10)
    - User Education Documents 1988-1997 & Undated (Box 10)
  - Black Dentistry in the 21st Century 1991 (Box 10)
  - Book Sale 1984-1995 (Box 10)
  - Buhr Storage Project 1987-1988 (Box 10)
  - Cataloging of Master's Thesis 1999 (Box 10)
  - Center for Research on Oral and Systemic Health (CROSH) circa 2001 (Box 10)
  - Circulation Rules and Policies Undated (Box 10)
  - Circulation Statistics and Volume Count 1954-1978, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Circulation Statistics and Volume Count 1980-1985, 1997 (Box 10)
  - Collection Budget 1971-1996, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Collection Development 1978, 1985-1999 (Box 10)
  - Collection Development Conspectus for the Medical and Health Sciences 1985 (Box 10)
  - Collection Development Special Purchases and Dealers 1947-1982 (Box 10)
  - Conservation and Treatment of Materials 1986-2006 (Box 10)
  - Conservation Proposal for the Digital Conservation of Historic Dental Journals 1998 (Box 10)
  - Dental Library Approval Plan for Ballen Booksellers International 1986-1995 (Box 10)
  - Dental Library Approval Plan for Rittenhouse Book Distributors 1991-1996 (Box 10)
  - Dental Library Approval Plan Profile for Collection Development with Matthews Medical and Scientific Book Company 1996 (Box 10)
  - Foreign Journals Study 1994-1996 (Box 10)
  - Gift to University of Zimbabwe 2005 (Box 10)
  - Interlibrary Loan 1994-1996 (Box 10)
  - Landmarks in Afro-American Dentistry Reference Guide Handout 2000 (Box 10)
  - Library Use Surveys 1954-1981, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Library Use Survey 1990-1991 (Box 11)
  - Library Website Homepage (printout) 2003 (Box 11)
  - Michigan State Law for the Protection of Libraries Posters undated (Box 11)
  - Policies for Scholarship and Promotion 2005-2006 (Box 11)
  - Reference Database Transaction Statistics 1991-1996 (Box 11)
  - Reference Letter 1996 (Box 11)
  - Reference Resource Guides 1996 & undated (Box 11)
  - Reference Service Request Form undated (Box 11)
  - Reference Service Studies 1980-1982 (Box 11)
  - Reference Statistics 1988-1997, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Reference Statistics Worksheet 1999 (Box 11)
  - Reserves 1997-1998 (Box 11)
  - Self-Guided Tour of the Dentistry Library Handout undated (Box 11)
  - Serials 1959-2002
    - Current Content Clinical Medicine Index Vol. 23 No. 29, 1995 (Box 11)
    - Foreign Serials 1986-1996 (Box 11)
    - Inventory undated (Box 11)
    - Serials Management 1987-2005 (Box 11)
    - Serials Management and Cancellations 1984-1998 (Box 11)
    - Serials Management and Title Changes 1985-1996 (Box 11)
    - Serials Management and Journal Selection Decisions 1987-1996 (Box 11)
    - Serials Management Notebook 1975-1981 (Box 11)
  - Sorting and Shelving Instructions undated (Box 11)
  - Special Collections Survey 1996 (Box 11)
  - Special Dental Classification and Subject Headings 1959-1962 & 1982 (Box 11)
  - Student Guidelines for Scholarship and Promotion 1994-1995 (Box 11)
  - Suggestions and Comments Form undated (Box 11)
  - "Taft the Tender, Taft the Tough: Founder of the U-M School of Dentistry" Exhibit 2000 (Box 11)
  - Technical Processing Manual Searching Orders 1999 (Box 11)
  - Technical Services Processing Worksheet undated (Box 11)
  - University of Michigan and Dentistry Library Orientation Guides and Materials 2002 (Box 11)
  - Uncatalogued Materials 1968-1982 (Box 11)
  - Vendocards for Photoduplication Forms 1997 (Box 11)
- Clippings Files 1962-1991
  The Clippings Files series, 1962-1991 (1.25 linear feet), is made up of clippings and vertical file material from media sources collected by the Dentistry Library regarding the School of Dentistry's faculty, staff, research, and public relations. The series has two sub-series for General Clippings File and Faculty, Staff, and Alumni Clippings. The Faculty, Staff, and Alumni Clippings sub-series includes files on specific faculty, staff, and selected alumni with newspaper clippings, biographical material, and scattered photographs.
  - General Clippings Files 1962-1991
    - Community Service and Outreach 1975-1988 (Box 12)
    - Conferences 1975-1991 (Box 12)
    - Dental Research Institute 1967-1989 (Box 12)
    - Dentistry and Medicine General Information 1965-1975 (Box 12)
    - Faculty and Staff 1968-1984 (Box 12)
    - Funding 1962-1971 (Box 12)
    - History 1925-2001 (Box 12)
    - History of Construction 1964-1974 (Box 12)
    - School of Dentistry 1962-1986 (Box 12)
    - Student Council Constitution 1967 (Box 12)
    - University of Michigan Dental Research 1975-1991 (Box 12)
    - Undergraduate and Graduate 1962-1981 (Box 12)
  - Faculty, Staff, and Alumni Clippings
    - Applegate, Oliver C. (Box 12)
    - Aseltine, Lyle F. (Box 12)
    - Asgar, Kamal (Box 12)
    - Ash, Major M. (Box 12)
    - Avery, James K. (Box 12)
    - Bagramian, Robert (Box 12)
    - Baer, Melvyn J. (Box 12)
    - Bonnette, Gerald H. (Box 12)
    - Bradley, Bruce (Box 12)
    - Brodbelt, Robert (Box 12)
    - Brooks, Sharon (Box 12)
    - Brown, William E., Jr. (Box 12)
    - Bunting, Russel W. (Box 12)
    - Burt, Brian (Box 12)
    - Caffesse, Raul G. (Box 12)
    - Carron, Susan (Box 12)
    - Cartwright, Charles B. (Box 12)
    - Charbeneau, Gerald T. (Box 12)
    - Charlick, Richard E. (Box 12)
    - Christiansen, Richard L. (Box 12)
    - Cheney, Edward A. (Box 12)
    - Cooper, Hugh Jr. (Box 12)
    - Corcoran, John F. Jr. (Box 12)
    - Courtney, Richard (Box 12)
    - Costich, Emmet R. (Box 12)
    - Craig, Robert G. (Box 12)
    - Crandell, Edward A. (Box 12)
    - Craven, Arthur H. (Box 12)
    - Crowley, Mary C. (Box 12)
    - Dinger, Earl J. (Box 12)
    - Desmond, Richard L. (Box 12)
    - Dingman, Reed O. (Box 12)
    - Doerr, Robert E. (Box 12)
    - Dowson, John (Box 12)
    - Drach, John (Box 12)
    - Drake, Rollin E. (Box 12)
    - Dunaway, Judith (Box 12)
    - Dziewiatkowski, Dominic D. (Box 12)
    - Easlick, Kenneth A. (Box 12)
    - Eklund, Stephen (Box 12)
    - Falasca, Raymond F. (Box 12)
    - Faust, Homer E. (Box 12)
    - Feigal, Robert J. (Box 12)
    - Feinberg, Stephen E. (Box 12)
    - Fetchiet, Richard R. (Box 12)
    - Fitzgerald, Mark (Box 12)
    - Raymond, Fonseca J. (Box 12)
    - Fusilier, Charles N. (Box 12)
    - Gibbons, Paul (Box 12)
    - Gilson, C. Mark (Box 12)
    - Gilson, Thomas D. (Box 12)
    - Gingles, Carl E. (Box 12)
    - Glickman, Gerald N. (Box 12)
    - Gobetti, John P. (Box 12)
    - Godwin, William C. (Box 12)
    - Han, Seong (Box 12)
    - Hard, Dorothy (Box 12)
    - Harris, James E. (Box 12)
    - Hartsook, Joseph T. (Box 12)
    - Hayes, Raymond L. (Box 12)
    - Hayward, James R. (Box 12)
    - Held, Harold W. (Box 12)
    - Hellman, Donald L. (Box 12)
    - Heys, Donald & Heys, Ronald (Box 12)
    - Henkel, John A. (Box 12)
    - Higuchi, William I. (Box 12)
    - Hiniker, Jerome J. (Box 12)
    - Hoff, Neville Soule (Box 12)
    - Jacobson, Jed J. (Box 12)
    - Jay, Philip (Box 12)
    - Jeserich, Paul H. (Box 12)
    - Johnston, Lysle E. (Box 12)
    - Kanar, Henry L. (Box 12)
    - Keevil, Joan M. (Box 12)
    - Kemper, John (Box 12)
    - Kerr, Donald A. (Box 12)
    - Kerry, Gloria (Box 12)
    - Kerschbaum, Wendy (Box 12)
    - Kingery, Richard H. (Box 12)
    - Knapp, Donald E. (Box 12)
    - Kohn, David H. (Box 12)
    - Kotowicz, William E. (Box 12)
    - Lang, Brien R. (Box 12)
    - Lang, W. Paul (Box 12)
    - Leinonen, Ellen (Box 12)
    - Loe, Harald (Box 12)
    - Loesche, Walter (Box 12)
    - Lorey, Robert E. (Box 12)
    - Loos, Paul J. (Box 12)
    - Lyons, Chalmers J. (Box 12)
    - McClatchey, Kenneth D. (Box 12)
    - McDowell, Glen C. (Box 12)
    - McNamara, James Jr. (Box 12)
    - Machen, J. Bernard (Dean) (Box 12)
    - Mann, William R. (Box 12)
    - Margeson, Ross D. (Box 13)
    - Millard, Herbert D. (Box 13)
    - Miller, Willoughby Dayton (Box 13)
    - Moore, George (Box 13)
    - Morawa, Arnold P. (Box 13)
    - More, Frederick G. (Box 13)
    - Morris, H.F. (Box 13)
    - Moyer, Ralph S. (Box 13)
    - Moyers, Robert E. (Box 13)
    - Myers, George E. (Box 13)
    - Nasjleti, Carlos E. (Box 13)
    - Nissle, Roland O. (Box 13)
    - Northrup, Philip (Box 13)
    - O'Brien, William J. (Box 13)
    - O'Connor, Patricia (Box 13)
    - O'Neal, Robert B. (Box 13)
    - Ostrander, Floyd D. (Box 13)
    - Peyton, Floyd A. (Box 13)
    - Polverini, Peter (Box 13)
    - Ponitz, Paul V. (Box 13)
    - Pratt, Leroy (Box 13)
    - Pritzel, Professor Susan (Box 13)
    - Ramfjord, Sigurd P. (Box 13)
    - Reese, James W. (Box 13)
    - Regezi, Joseph A. (Box 13)
    - Richards, Albert G. (Box 13)
    - Rickert, Ura Garfield (Box 13)
    - Robinson, Emerson (Box 13)
    - Ross, Sylvia (Box 13)
    - Rowe, Nathanial H. (Box 13)
    - Russell, Albert Lee (Box 13)
    - Schultz, Louis C. (Box 13)
    - Schwartz, Walter (Box 13)
    - Segat, Leon (Box 13)
    - Seger, Susan (Box 13)